Finding Aid for the Lawrence Morton Papers LSC.1522
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Research Material
  - Stravinsky, Articles About
    - Morton, Lawrence--Footnotes to Stravinsky studies: Le Sacre du Printemps., 1979. (Box 32)
      Tempo (March) 128: 9-16.
    - Maconie, Robin--Stravinsky's final cadence., 1972. (Box 32)
      Tempo 103: 18-23.
    - Stravinsky, Vera--Unpublished letters from Igor Stravinsky to Ernst Roth., 1972. (Box 32)
      Tempo 98: 18-19.
    - Keller, Hans--Stravinsky's performance of 'Agon': A report., 1972. (Box 32)
      Tempo 100: 19-22.
      Originally published in Tempo in 1959.
    - Spies, Claudio--Impressions after an exhibition., 1972. (Box 32)
      Tempo 102: 2-9.
    - Helm, Everett--Igor Stravinsky's 'Abraham and Isaac'., 1964. (Box 32)
      Tempo (Winter) 71: 27.
    - Josipovici, Gabriel--'The rake's progress': Some thoughts on the libretto., 1975. (Box 32)
      Tempo (June) 113: 2-13.
    - Norris, Geoffrey--Books., 1976. (Box 32)
      Tempo (September) 118: 39-40.
      A review of L.S. Dyachkova, comp., I.F. Stravinsky: Stat'i I materialy (Moscow: Sovetsky Kompozitor).
    - Britten, Benjamin--Britten on 'Oedipus Rex' and 'Lady Macbeth'., 1977. (Box 32)
      Tempo (March) 120: 10-12.
      Also includes Robin Holloway review of Francis Routh, Stravinsky (The master musicians, London: J.M. Dent).
    - Warrack, John--Stravinsky's 'The flood'., 1963. (Box 32)
      Tempo (Summer) 65: 13-14.
    - Holloway, Robin--Books., 1980. (Box 32)
      Tempo 135: 31-33.
      A review of Vera Stravinsky and Robert Craft, Stravinsky in pictures and documents (London: Hutchinson).
    - Payne, Anthony--Stravinsky's 'The flood'., 1964. (Box 32)
      Tempo (Autumn) 70: 2-8.
    - Craft, Robert--'Le Sacre du Printemps': The revisions., 1977. (Box 32)
      Tempo (September) 122: 2-8.
    - Evans, Peter--Stravinsky: Information and illumination., 1961. (Box 32)
      Tempo (Spring) 57: 2-5.
      The title of this article is listed on cover Stravinsky: Information and illusion. This is a review of Roman Vlad, Stravinsky and Igor Stravinsky and Robert Craft, Memories and commentaries.
    - Schonberger, Elmer, and Louis Andriessen--The Apollonian Clockwork: Extracts from a book., 1982. (Box 32)
      Translated by Jeff Hamburg.
      Tempo (June) 141: 3-21.
      Also includes Clare Hogan, Threni': Stravinsky's 'debt' to Krenek (pp.22-29).
    - Stein, Erwin--Strawinsky's 'Septet'., 1954. (Box 32)
      Tempo (Spring) 31: 7-10.
    - Roth, Ernst, Eric Walter White, David Matthews, Susan Bradshaw, Wilfrid Mellers, Douglas Young and Laelia Goehr--Igor Stravinsky 17 June 1882-6 April 1971. (Box 32)
      Tempo 97.
      Festshrift. Also Ten canons and epitaphs by Berio, Berkeley, Birtwistle, Blacher, Maxwell Davies, Denisov, Maw, Tippett, Schnittke, Wood.
    - Craft, Robert--A note on Gesualdo and Strawinsky., 1957. (Box 32)
      Tempo 45: 5-7.
    - White, Eric Walter--Stravinsky and Debussy., 1962. (Box 32)
      Tempo (Spring/Summer) 61/62: 2-5.
      Also includes Colin Mason Serial procedures in the Ricercar II of Stravinsky's 'Cantata', Donald Mitchell Stravinsky and new-classicism and Herbert Read, Stravinsky and the muses.
    - Keller, Hans--Strawinsky's performance of 'Agon'., 1959. (Box 32)
      Tempo (Winter) 50: 22-25.
      Also includes drawings by Milein Cosman.
    - Keller, Hans--Conversations with Igor Stravinsky., 1959. (Box 32)
      Tempo (Autumn) 52: 16, 21-25.
      Book review.
    - Mason, Colin--Strawinsky's contribution to chamber music., 1957. (Box 32)
      Tempo (Spring) 43: 6-16.
    - Stein, Erwin--Igor Stravinsky: Canticum sacrum ad honorem sancti Marce nominis., 1956. (Box 32)
      Tempo (Summer) 40: 3-5.
    - Keller, Hans--In memoriam Dylan Thomas--Strawinsky's Schoenbergian technique., 1955. (Box 32)
      Tempo (Spring) 35: 13-20.
    - Mason, Colin--Strawinsky's newest works., 1960. (Box 32)
      Tempo (Spring/Summer) 53/54: 2-10.
    - Lindlar, Heinrich--Igor Strawinsky: Cantata., 1953. (Box 32)
      Tempo (Spring) 27: 28-33.
    - White, Eric Walter--The rake's progress., 1951. (Box 32)
      Tempo (Summer) 20: 10-22.
      Also includes W.H. Auden Some reflections on opera as a medium and Strawinsky's 'The rake's progress': Introduction, synopsis and illustrations.
    - Mason, Colin--Stravinsky's new work., 1961. (Box 32)
      Tempo (Autumn) 59: 5-14.
      A sermon, a narrative and a prayer.
    - Shapero, Harold--Igor Stravinsky: Cantata for soprano, tenor, female chorus, and a small instrumental ensemble., 1953. (Box 33)
      Notes (September) 10(4): 681-82.
    - Sternfeld, Frederick W.--Some Russian folk songs in Stravinsky's 'Petrouchka'., 1945. (Box 33)
      Notes (March) 2(2): 95-107.
    - Morton, Lawrence--Igor Strawinsky: Scherzo a la russe, symphonic version, Tango [1940], new orchestration, 1953 and Tchaikovsky Bluebird--pas de deux., 1955. (Box 33)
      Notes (September) 12(4): 656-57.
    - Morton, Lawrence--Igor Stravinsky: Movements for piano and orchestra., 1962. (Box 33)
      Notes (Winter) 20(1): 124-26.
    - Vinton, John--Stravinsky: The composer and his works, by E.W. White., 1968. (Box 33)
      Notes (March) 24(3): 479-80.
    - Seay, Albert--The Norton critical scores [including Petrouchka]., 1968. (Box 33)
      Notes (September) 25(1): 119-121.
    - Kerr, Harrison--Igor Stravinsky: Four Norwegian moods., 1945. (Box 33)
      Notes (June) 2(3): 179-180.
    - Morton, Lawrence--Conversations with Igor Stravinsky, by Igor Stravinsky and Robert Craft., 1959. (Box 33)
      Notes (September) 16(4): 558-59.
    - Hill, Richard S.--Igor Stravinsky: Scenes de ballet for orchestra., 1945. (Box 33)
      Notes (December) 3(1): 70-71.
    - Rogers, Bernard--Igor Stravinsky: Le Sacre du Printemps., 1946. (Box 33)
      Notes (March) 3(2): 184-185.
    - Meyers, Emerson--Igor Stravinsky: Sonata for two pianos., 1946. (Box 33)
      Notes (September) 3(4): 382-383.
      Also includes William Schempf on Elegie for Viola.
    - Luening, Otto--Igor Stravinsky: Symphony in three movements., 1946. (Box 33)
      Notes (December) 4(1): 108-109.
    - Citkowitz, Isreal--Igor Stravinsky: Ode, elegiacal chant in three parts, for orchestra., 1947. (Box 33)
      Notes (September) 4(4): 486-7.
    - Shapero, Harold--Igor Stravinsky: The rake's progress., 1952. (Box 33)
      Notes (June) 9(3): 488-89.
    - Lang, Paul Henry--Expositions and developments, by Igor Stravinsky and Robert Craft., 1963. (Box 33)
      Notes (Spring) 22(2): 223-24.
    - Chase, Gilbert--Stravinsky: His life and work by Eric Walter White., 1948. (Box 33)
      Notes (June) 5(3): 371.
    - Stevens, Halsey--Stravinsky, by Roman Vlad & Memories and commentaries, by Igor Stravinsky and Robert Craft., 1961. (Box 33)
      Notes (June) 13(3): 411-12.
    - Fox, Charles Warren--Igor Stravinsky: Orpheus & Concerto in re for string orchestra., 1948. (Box 33)
      Notes (September) 5(4): 519-520.
    - Dahl, Ingolf--Igor Stravinsky: Mass for mixed chorus and double wind quintet., 1949. (Box 33)
      Notes (June) 6(3): 490-491.
    - Weinant, Elwyn A--Igor Stravinsky: Requiem Canticles, for contralto and bass soli, chorus, and orchestra., 1960. (Box 33)
      Notes (June) 25(4): 830-33.
    - Morton, Lawrence--Igor Strawinsky: Two songs for baritone and orchestra., 1954. (Box 33)
      Notes (March) 11(2): 284.
    - Vinton, John--Stravinsky, by Roman Vlad., 1969. (Box 33)
      Notes (March) 25(3): 496-97.
    - Mooser, R. Aloys, redacteur--Le Symphonie de psaumes de Strawinsky., 1931. (Box 34)
      Dissonances Revue Independente (Avril--Conches-Geneve) 4(4): 95-98.
    - Souvchintsky, Pierre--Igor Strawinsky., 1946. (Box 34)
      Countrepoints (Fevrier) 2: 19-30.
    - Koechlin, Charles (letter), and Goldbeck, Fred (response)--Autour de Poetique Musicale., 1946. (Box 34)
      Countrepoints (Mai/Juin) 4: 49-53.
    - Goldbeck, Fred--Note sur la Symphonie en trois mouvements de Strawinsky., 1946. (Box 34)
      Countrepoints (December) 5: 49.
    - Myers, Rollo H.--Stravinsky on music., 1960. (Box 34)
      The Chesterian (Winter) 34(201): 85-88.
      Also includes Arthur Dennington, The three orchestrations of Stravinsky's 'firebird' (pp.89-94).
    - Goldbeck, Fred--La theorique D'Igor Strawinsky., 1946. (Box 34)
      Countrepoints (Mars-Avril) 3: 12-30.
    - Craft, Robert--Stravinsky, Diaghilev, and Misia Sert., 1977-78. (Box 34)
      Ballet Revue, Dance Research Foundation (New York) 6(4): 66-77.
    - Homenaje a Igor Strawinsky en la LXX anniversario de su nacimento., 1952. (Box 34)
      Musica Revista Trimestral de Los Conservatorios Espanoles (Madrid).
    - Boulez, Pierre--Trajectoires: Ravel, Stravinsky, Schoenberg., n.d. (Box 34)
      Countrepoints 6: 122-142.
    - Shepard, John--The Stravinsky Nachlass: A provisional checklist of music manuscripts., 1984. (Box 34)
      Notes (June) 40(4): 719-750.
      Also includes Richard Turuskin, The music of Igor Stravinsky, by Pieter Van den Toorn (pp.770-772).
    - DeVoto, Mark--Stravinsky and the piano, by Charles M. Joseph., 1984. (Box 34)
      Notes (December) 41(2): 275-6.
    - Hamilton, David--Expositions and developments & Dialogues and a diary, by Igor Stravinsky & Robert Craft., 1970. (Box 34)
      Notes (March) 26(3): 531-532.
      Also includes William W. Austin The rite of spring' [facsimile edition] by Igor Stravinsky.
    - Hamilton, David--'Themes and conclusions', by Igor Stravinsky., 1973. (Box 34)
      Notes (December) 30(2): 286-7.
    - Cyr, Louis--Strawinsky: Sein Nachlass, sein Bild., 1985. (Box 34)
      Notes (December) 42(2): 288.
      Review.
    - Hamilton, David--Stravinsky in pictures and documents, by Vera Stravinsky and Robert Craft., 1979. (Box 34)
      Notes (Sept) 36(1): 88-89.
    - No author--Notes for Notes., 1983. (Box 34)
      Notes (December) 40(2): 271-72.
      On the purchase of the Stravinsky archives by the Paul Sacher Foundation.
    - Payne, Anthony--Stravinsky's Abraham and Isaac and Elegy for J.F.K., 1965. (Box 35)
      Tempo (Summer) 73: 12-15.
    - The Quarterly Journal of the Library of Congress., 1967. (Box 35)
      (January) 24(1).
      In L.M.'s hand: [Stravinsky] pp.62-63, 71.
    - The Quarterly Journal of the Library of Congress., 1966. (Box 35)
      (January) 23(1).
      In L.M.'s hand: [Stravinsky] pp.26-28.
    - The Quarterly Journal of the Library of Congress., 1969. (Box 35)
      (January) 26(1).
      In L.M.'s hand: [Stravinsky] pp.26, 35-36, 41.
    - The Quarterly Journal of the Library of Congress., 1971. (Box 35)
      (January) 28(1).
      In L.M.'s hand: [Stravinsky] pp.55-56, 68.
    - The Quarterly Journal of the Library of Congress., 1977. (Box 35)
      (January) 34(1).
      In L.M.'s hand: [Stravinsky] p.7.
    - White, Eric Walter--First performances: Two new memorial works by Stravinsky., 1965. (Box 35)
      Tempo (Autumn) 74: 19-21.
      Variations, Aldous Huxley in memoriam and Introitus, T.S. Eliot in memoriam.
    - Hopkins, G.W.--Stravinsky's chord's (I)., 1966. (Box 35)
      Tempo (Spring) 76: 6-12.
    - Hopkins, G.W.--Stravinsky's chords (II)., 1966. (Box 35)
      Tempo (Summer) 77: 2-9.
    - Roth, E., P. Souvtchinsky, J. Warrick, A. Payne, R. Smalley, G. Crosse, A. Ginastera, A. Goehr, J. Tavener, W. Mellers, E. White, J. Ogden, S. Walsh--Stravinsky's 85th birthday., 1967. (Box 35)
      Tempo (Summer) 81.
      Also compositions by R.R. Bennett, H. Birtwistle, G. Crosse, P.M. Davies, B. Dennis, M. Finnissy, N., Maw, J. Ogdon, R. Smalley, T. Souster, J. Tavener, M. Williamson.
    - Keller, Hans--The contemporary problem., 1967. (Box 35)
      Tempo (Winter) 83: 24-25.
    - Souvtchinsky, Pierre--Thoughts on Stravinsky's 'Requiem canticles'., 1968. (Box 35)
      Tempo (Autumn) 86: 6-7.
    - Whittall, Arnold--Thematicism in Stravinsky's 'Abraham and Isaac'., 1969. (Box 35)
      Tempo (Summer) 89: 12-16.
    - Russell, Thomas W. III--Madame (Imprimatur Gallery in St. Paul has assembled the colorful works of Vera (Mrs. Igor) Stravinsky., 1985. (Box 37)
      Twin Cities (November) 8(11): 120-130.
    - Lindlar, Heinrich--Igor Strawinsky im Spiegel seiner Sakralmusik from Stilportrats der Neuen Musik., 1961. (Box 39)
      Berlin: Verlag Merseberger: 32-41.
    - Szersvovicz, Patrick--Stravinsky et les autres., n.d. [1980].; Photocopy. (Box 67)
      Diapason (Paris): 37-38.
    - Boucourechliev, Andre--Dossier Stravinsky a Paris., 1980. (Box 67)
      Harmonie (September): 36-38.
      Photocopy. Inscribed: To Lawrence Morton very cordially AB. Review of Festival Automne 1980.
    - Marnat, Marcelle--Pourquoi un Festival Stravinsky., n.d. [1980].; Photocopy. (Box 67)
      Diapason (Paris): 30-34.
    - No Author--Metropolitan Stravinsky celebration a milestone., 1981-82. (Box 67)
      Boosey & Hawkes, Inc. Newsletter (Winter--Spring) 13(2): 1, 9, 14.
    - Biette, Jean Claude--Stravinsky a Venise un certain sens du sacre., n.d. [1980]. (Box 67)
      Diapason (Paris): 40-41.
    - Blazhkov, Igor--I. Stravinsky's letters to N. Roerich., 1966. (Box 73)
      A typescript English translation of the letters is inserted.
      Soverskaia muzyka (August 8): organ Soiuza kompozitorov SSSR i Ministerstva kul'tury SSSR. Inscribed before table of contents:
      Mr. Morton, Please turn your attention to pp.57-63. I wish you great success with your noble labour at the monograph about our great countryman. Sincerely yours, Igor Blazhkov.
    - Curjel, Hans--Strawinsky oder die Kunstlerische atmosphere von Paris., 1929.; Photographic negatives and proofs. (Box 74)
      Melos (April).
    - Russian newspapers--Paris., n.d.; Photographic negatives and prints. (Box 74)
    - Photographic prints--For translation., n.d. (Box 74)
      Prints of negatives from other envelopes in German.
    - Ferroud, P.O.--The role of the abstract in Igor Stravinsky's work., n.d.; Photographic negatives and proofs. (Box 74)
      The Chesterian.
    - Poulenc, Francis--Igor Stravinsky., 1941.; Photographic negatives and proofs. (Box 74)
      L'Information Musicale (3 Janvier) 1(7).
    - Honegger, Arthur--Franck et Strawinsky., 1941.; Photographic negatives and proofs. (Box 74)
      L'Information Musicale (19 Septembre) 2(38).
    - Taylor, Ronald--Stravinsky and the problems of 20th century music., Photographic negatives and proofs. (Box 74)
      Cambridge Journal 6(6).
    - Browne, Andre J.--Aspects of Stravinsky's work., 1930.; Photographic negatives and proofs. (Box 74)
      Music and Letters (October).
    - Blatter der Staatsoper VIII: 19 February 1923 Enlarged (Includes re-shooting of bad film., n.d.; Photographic negatives. (Box 74)
    - Mersmann, Hans, et al--Strawinsky: Oedipus Rex., n.d.; Photographic negatives and prints. (Box 74)
      Melos (Mainz), 4(28).
    - Flanner, Janet--Profiles: Russian firebird., 1935. (Box 81)
      The New Yorker (January 5) 10(47): 23-28.
    - Strabel, Heinrich--Strawinksy: hors classe., 1962. (Box 81)
      Melos (Juni) 29(6): 177-178.
    - Various--Strawinsky unter uns., 1962. (Box 81)
      Melos (June) 29(6): 180-185.
    - Briner, Andres--Neues von Strawinsky uber sich selbst., 1962. (Box 81)
      Melos (Juni) 29(6): 186-188.
    - Molinari, Cesare--Osservazioni sui manifesti del teatro futurista., 1959. (Box 81)
      La Biennale de Venezia (December) 9(36-37): 72-76.
    - Rosenfeld, Paul--The mystery of Persephone., 1935. (Box 81)
      The New Republic (April 3) 132(1061): 213-14.
    - No author--Stravinsky week at the Eastman school., 1966. (Box 81)
      Rochester Review (Summer): 3-5.
    - Craft, Robert--Stravinsky's return 'A Russian diary'., 1963. (Box 81)
      Encounter (June) 20(6): 33-48.
    - Craft, Robert--With Aldous Huxley., 1965. (Box 81)
      Encounter (November) 25(5): 10-16.
    - Stadler, Edmund--Rene Auberjonois, Charles-Ferdinand Ramuz und Igor Strawinsky., 1964. (Box 81)
      Du Atlantis (November): 18-24.
      Also includes Manuel Gasser, Serge de Diaghilew und die Maler der Ecole de Paris.
    - Thomson, Virgil--Stravinsky's operas., 1974. (Box 81)
      Musical Newsletter (Fall): 3-7, 22.
    - Berkeley, Lennox--Igor Stravinsky - A centenary tribute., 1982. (Box 81)
      The Musical Times (June) 123(1672): 395-402.
    - Asbury, Edith Evans--Stravinsky estate battle settled., n.d. (Box 81)
      [New York Times].
      The publication is not identified, however the type style and the identification of the addresses of all New York residents suggests the Times.
    - Harrison, Jay S.--Fourscore for Stravinsky., 1962.; 2 copies. (Box 81)
      Show (June) 2(6): 38-39.
    - Nabokov, Nicolas--Stravinsky - Fifteen and three score., 1957. (Box 81)
      High Fidelity (June): 33-44, 99-104.
    - Pasler, Jann--Stravinsky and the Apaches., 1982. (Box 81)
      The Musical Times (June)123 (1672): 403-407.
      Inscibed To my very dear helper and advisor. Jann.
    - Briner, Andreas--Guilaume de Machaut 1958/58 oder Strawinskys Movements for piano and orchestra., 1960. (Box 81)
      Melos (Juni) 27(6): 184-186.
    - Kraemer, Uwe--Four Norwegian Moods by Igor Strawinsky., 1972. (Box 84)
      Melos (March/April) 2: 80-84.
      Photocopy of German article.
    - Shattuck, Roger--The devil's dance., 1983. (Box 84)
      The New Republic (December 26): 26-32.
    - Mudrick, Marvin--The last great composer., 1984.; Photocopy. 10 leaves. (Box 84)
      The Hudson Review (Summer): 223-238.
    - Karlinsky, Simon--Stravinsky and Russian pre-literate theater., 1983.; Off-print. (Box 84)
      19th Century Music (Spring) 6(3): 232-240.
      Inscribed For Lawrence Morton, Stravinsky's friend, a paper he has already heard. W/best regards Simon Karlinsky.
      See letter from Karlinsky (21 October 1982) in Box 85.
    - Yates, Peter--Igor Stravinsky: The final maturity., 1973.; Photocopy. 8 leaves. (Box 84)
      TriQuarterly (Fall) 28: 365-379.
      Inscribed: For Lawrence Morton--This piece which I commissioned 10 years ago. S. Karlinsky.
    - Wise, C. Stanley--Impressions of Igor Strawinsky., 1916.; Photocopy. 18 leaves. (Box 84)
      The Musical Quarterly (April) 2(2): 249-256.
    - Chenneviere, Rudhyar D.--The two trends of modern music in Stravinsky's works., 1919.; Photocopy. 16 leaves. (Box 84)
      The Musical Quarterly (April) 5(2): 169-174.
    - Pasler, Jann--Stravinsky's visualization of music., 1981.; Photocopy. 4 leaves. (Box 84)
      Dance Magazine (April): 66-69.
    - Pasler, Jann--Stravinsky and the Apaches., 1982.; Photocopy. 5 leaves. (Box 84)
      The Musical Times (June): 403-407.
    - Morton, Lawrence--Footnotes to Stravinsky studies: 'Le Sacre du printemps'., 1979. (Box 84)
      See letter from Irving Kolodin in Box 85.
    - White, Eric Walter, and Jeremy Noble--Stravinsky, Igor (Fyodorovitch)., n.d. [1980].; Photocopy. (Box 84)
      New Grove dictionary of music and musicians. London: Macmillan Publishers, Limited.
      Includes article on Fyodor Ignat'yevich Stravinsky by Jennifer Spencer.
    - Joseph, Charles M.--Stravinsky's 'Piano scherzo' (1902) in perspective: A new starting point., 1981.; Photocopy. (Box 85)
      Musical Quarterly 67: 82-93.
    - Karlinsky, Simon--The composer's workshop., 1970. (Box 85)
      The Nation (June 15): 730-733.
      Review of Retrospectives and conclusions, The rite of spring--sketches, and I. Vershinina,Stravinsky's early ballets.
    - No Author--Deliberately dry., 1948.; Photocopy. (Box 85)
      Time (May 10): 48.
    - Porter, Andrew--Triptych., 1981. (Box 85)
      The New Yorker (December 21): 134-137.
    - Henry, Derrick--Igor Stravinsky: In memoriam., 1971. (Box 85)
      UCLA Daily Bruin (April 4).
    - Hamilton, David--The rake's progress: A novel work vividly aware of its past., 1985.; Photocopy. (Box 85)
      Opus (October): 24-26.
    - Schillaci, Dan--SFO's 'Rake's progress' - without the 'flaws'., 1981.; Photocopy. (Box 85)
      The Alberquerque Tribune (July 31): B-1.
    - F., A. [?]--Concerning Stravinsky: Carlos Salzedo speaks of the art and personality of the Russian composer., 1924.; Photocopy. (Box 85)
      The Musical Digest (December 30): 17.
    - Malkiel, Henrietta--'Modernists have ruined modern music', Stravinsky says., 1925.; Photocopy. (Box 85)
      Musical America (January 10).
    - Lieberson, Goddard--Igor Stravinsky: A tribute by Goddard Lieberson., 1971.; Photocopy. (Box 85)
      The Gramophone (June/November): 19.
    - Craft, Robert--Stravinsky in the Twenties., 1974. (Box 123)
      New York Review of Books (2 May) 29-33.
      Includes a letter to the editors from Theodore Strawinsky and Craft reply, defending his critique of Mr. Strawinsky's, Catherine and Igor Strawinsky.
    - Craft, Robert--Fit to print: The changing times., 1972. (Box 123)
      New York Review of Books (6 April): 21-22.
      Critique of Lillian Libman, And music at the close.
    - Hamilton, D.--Letter to the editor., 1972. (Box 123)
      New York Review of Books (20 April): 42-43.
      A defense of yet to be released Libman book (And music at the close) w/reply from Craft.
    - Craft, Robert--The press: Freedom from as well as of., 1972. (Box 123)
      New York Review of Books (29 June): 27-28.
      More on Libman, And music at the close.
    - Craft, Robert--Venice: Paragraphs from a diary., 1972. (Box 123)
      New York Review of Books (5 October): 28-30.
    - Craft, Robert, and W. Harkins--Stravinsky's Svadebka (Les Noces)., 1972. (Box 123)
      New York Review of Books (14 December): 23-31.
    - Craft, Robert--Assisting Stravinsky., 1982. (Box 123)
      Atlantic (December): 68-69, 70-74.
    - Craft, Robert--Catherine and Igor Stravinsky., 1979. (Box 123)
      New York Review of Books (22 November): 33-36.
    - Craft, Robert--Compositions., 1983. (Box 123)
      New York Review of Books (22 December): 50-52.
      Book review & Stravinsky/Gould.
    - Craft, Robert--My life with Stravinsky., 1982. (Box 123)
      New York Review of Books (10 June): 6-10.
    - Craft, Robert--The unknown Stravinsky., 1974. (Box 123)
      New York Review of Books (21 February): 15-21.
    - Craft, Robert--Stravinsky in America., 1974. (Box 123)
      New York Review of Books (8 August): 26-32.
    - Craft, Robert--Nijinsky and 'Le Sacre'., 1976. (Box 123)
      New York Review of Books (15 April): 36-39.
    - Craft, Robert--Igor Stravinsky: Obiter dicta., 1977. (Box 123)
      New York Review of Books (17 March): 27-32.
      Includes a letter from Ned Rorem (From 14 April issue) about errors in this article and Craft's reply.
    - Craft, Robert--Pages from a chronicle., 1971. (Box 123)
      New York Review of Books (25 February): 20-30.
    - Craft, Robert--Stravinsky: Problems for the biographers., 1973. (Box 123)
      New York Review of Books (9 August): 14-18.
  - Stravinsky, Articles By (Also Published Letters)
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Igor Stravinsky on Beethoven piano sonatas., 1970. (Box 10)
      Harper's (May) 240(1440): 34-46.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--An interview with Stravinsky., 1965. (Box 10)
      New York Review of Books (3 June) 4(9): 4-5.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--A realm of truth: 'The Beethoven Quartets' by Joseph Kerman., 1968. (Box 10)
      New York Review of Books (26 September) 11(5): 3-4.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--A cure for VD (The title is Mr. Stravinsky's own)., 1964. (Box 10)
      Listen: A Music Monthly (September/October): 1-2.
      The title may be I.S.'s only contribution. L.M. wrote this letter to the editor for Stravinsky.
      (See Box 69 Letters to the music editor--Los Angeles Times folder).
    - Stravinsky, Igor--On manners music, and mortality., 1968. (Box 10)
      Harper's (February) 236(1413): 41-47.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--Music and the statistical age., 1966. (Box 10)
      Commentary (September) 42(3): 49-52.
    - Stravinsky, Igor--The Diaghilev I knew., 1953. (Box 10)
      The Atlantic (November) 192(5): 33-36.